Guide to the Pacific Improvement Company Records, 1901-1966 JL017
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Cf JL 16 - S.F.B. Morse and Del Monte Properties
  - “S.F.B. Morse - Tahoe Land”. Correspondence, deed, marriage license (Perkins - Barrow - French), correspondence and map re: Donner McKinney State Road near Lake Tahoe, S.F.B.M. sells land to State of Calif. so that road might be constructed., Dates: 12/31/13 - 5/17/17. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - “S.F.B. Morse and Fleishacker, Monterey Property.”. Correspondence, agreement re: partnership Fleishacker to S.F.B.M., 2/3/19. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - “S.F.B. Morse, B.L. Thane/Pac. Coast Steel Syn, Iron and Steel Venture”. Agreements, indentures of lease (with P.I. Co.)., Dates: 1/16/1917 - 8/27/21. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - “S.F.B. Horse - Personal Insurance”. Policies and receipts., Dates: 5/13/18 - 7/10/41. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - “S.F.B. Morse - Personal Business Dealings”. Correspondence, agreements, options, leases, deeds, license, agreement, insurance policy for his boat., Dates: 5/21/15 - 8/31/34. (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - “Monterey Peninsula - Quitclaim Correspondence, Release of Covenants”. Quitclaim deed with related correspondence and map, legal action against P.I. Co. and others in Superior Court, other correspondence, release of restrictive covenant., Dates: 4/12/1915 - 1/16/68 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - “Del Monte Hotel”. Bank book, contract, proposal of elevator installation made by Otis Co., promisory note, hearing before the Industrial Accident Commission Redlands v. P.I. Co., sample of mail forwarding address index cards., Dates: 9/1/10 - 10/11/15. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - “Del Monte Light and Power Co.”. Articles of incorporation in Calif., by-laws, notices of Stockholder's meetings and blank proxies, proceedings re: applications made by Del Monte L & P Co. to various California State Commissions (R.R. and Corporate), statement of cost of generating power for Hotal Del Monte, agreements., Dates: 3/12/19 - 8/14/19. (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - “Del Monte Properties”. Bank book and interorganizational memos, 12/16/35 - 9/6/39. (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - “Del Monte Properties”. Brochures and maps, Jan. 1926 - Nov. 1938. (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - “Lake Majella, Monterey County”. Notations and sketch, contract for sand, July 11, 1913. (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - “Monterey County Water Works”. Correspondence re: taxes and accounting opinion of Calif. State R.R. Commission in case of City of Monterey v. Monterey County Water Works. Polhemus' resignation as secretary., Dates: 6/14/13 - 11/20/16. (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - “Agreements - Monterey Peninsula”. List of agreements is 1st item most of agreements on list included., Dates: 6/9/03 - 0/20/18. (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - “Misc. Leases - Monterey Peninsula”. Includes list of leases., Dates: 11/21/10 - 11/1/18. (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - “War Department - Revocable License for Water Main, U.S. Military Reservation - Monterey”. Correspondence from Army Quartermasters, 12/31/03 - 12/27/04. (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - “Pacific Grove Lands/Monterey County”. Contracts for deeds, lease, report for litigation, correspondence re: deeds, document of consent and subordination., Dates: 7/17/93 - 6/8/64. (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - “Pebble Beach, Monterey County”. Contract for deed and mortgage, (June - July 1914). (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - “Pebble Beach - Abstract to lot 17 and Parts of 18 and 41”. Includes maps, (2) abstracts of titles made: 1. 2., April 28, 1920. Feb. 23, 1922. (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - “Pebble Beach, Monterey County - Karmany Mortgage”. Fire insurance policy, deed of trust, mortgages, deeds, reconveyance of trustees, waiver of priority of mortgage., Dates: 11/1/16 - 3/15/22. (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - “Pebble Beach - Report on Cost of Development ”., 5/31/20 (Box 17, Folder 22)
- Carbon Hill Coal, Misc. Taxes, Corporation Papers, Old Monterey Water Works.
  - “Carbon Hill Coal Co. Agreements”. List of contents included, dates: 2/3/15 - 7/20/23. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - “Midvale Steel & Ordance Co. - July - Nov. 1918”. Correspondence, resignations of all C.H.C.C. officers, preliminary agreements, final agreement M.S. & O. Co. and C.H.C.C., Aug. 1918. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - “Low Temperature Distillation of Coals”. Report made by R.J. Walzen and others (A.S. Knowles, V.T. Smith, C.V. McIntire) for C.H.C.C. and B.L. Thane -, June 13, 1922. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - “Annual Meeting Notices - C.H.C.Co. ”. Includes proxies, proof of publication etc., 1907-1929 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - “Misc. - 1. P.I. Co. Subsidiaries, a. Financial Information b. Stockholders, 2. Sale of Monterey Peninsula Property”. la. Handwritten notations and ledger sheets re: financial condition of various P.I. Co. subsidiaries and townsites - mostly lb. Typed list of stockholder and his holding in each P.I. Co. subsidiary, 2. correspondence and reports re: sale of P.I. Co. Monterey Peninsula land to Herbert Fleishacker and Morse, undated, 1916 - 1919. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - “Misc. - Reports 1918 - 1919”. Schedule of liquid assets of P.I. Co. record of paid dividends, reports on the result of the sale and earnings of companies sold to Fleishacker with Monterey Peninsula property, Del Monte Properties Co. agreements, lists of P.I. Co. townsites with “present” and proposed values, digest of mechanics of the lien law., (11/15/18) (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - “Misc. - Reports 1921 - 1923”. Report on feasibility study re: sale of remaining P.I. Co. holdings, memos and information sent by Stipp to J. Beaumont for a report re: P.I. Co. financial situation in early dates of memos - includes financial statements for the New York office, 1915, Nov. 1923 - 1915 - 1916. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Reports on P.I. Co. Subsidiaries and Details of P.I. Co. Real Estate ”., 1923 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - “Carbon Hill Coal Co. - Contracts and Leases”. List of contents included, dates: 1914 - 1920. (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - “P.I. Co. Meeting Notices, Proxies, etc.”. Proof of publication of notices., Dates 1917 - 1934. (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - “Minutes of the Meeting of the Operating Depts.”. Held, 5/19 and 10/23, 1924. (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - “Subsidiary Cos. - Meeting Notices”. Proxies and proof of publication., Dates: 1920 - 1935. (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - “Contracts”. P.I. Co. contracts list of contracts in folder., 1908 - 1920 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - “Bills of Sale to P.I. Co.”. D.H. Greenslate, 2/17/17. (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - “Agreements, P.I. Co.”. List of agreements included on folder, dates: 1907 - 1935. (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - “Leases, P.I. Co.”. List of leases included on folder., Dates: 1906 - 1918. (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - “Notices to Vacate”. List of notices included on folder., Dates: 1917 - 1918. (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - “Es ate Papers, Degrees of Distribution, Powers of Attorney”. Estate papers of C.P. Huntington and Mary Hopkins, powers of attorney Searles to Thomas E. Stellman and T.H. Hubbard, (7/13/88). (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - “Annual Report Pacific Improvement Co., ”., 1933 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - “Annual Report Pacific Improvement Co. ”., 1934 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - “Report to Board of Directors of P.I. Co. re: the Reorganization of the Pittsburg, Shawmut and Northern Rwy. Co. ”., July 1/35 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - “Reports, Statements, etc.”. List of contents on folder, dates: 1893 - 1919. (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - “Letters”. List of contents on folder., Dates: 1914 - 1918. (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - “Option, Indenture of Trust, Rights of Way”. List of contents, dates: 1908, 1918. (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - “Leases”. P.I. Co., list of contents on folder., Dates: 1915 - 1918. (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - “Agreements”. P.I. Co., list of contents on folder., Dates: 1883 - 1921. (Box 18, Folder 26)
- Corporation Papers, Monterey Water Works, Castle Crags, Hope Ranch.
  - “Del Monte Garage - J.L. Murphy”. Listof contents on folder, correspondence, agreements, mortgages, bill of sale., Dates: 1/6/16 - 2/24/17. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - “Deeds”. List of contents on folder, Stanford Board of Trustees to P.I. Co. typed copies of old deeds., (2/13/17), Dates: 1877 - 1906. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - “Deeds”. Continued from 19-2, list of contents on folder, old conveyances of right of way old conveyances of water rights old notices of water appropriation others, (1883, 1890), (1883 - 1905), (1893, 1905), (1906, 1916). (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - “Reports”. List of contents on folder, miscellaneous - P.I. Co., Dates: 10/14/13 - 8/28/18. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - “Miscellaneous Letters - Old”. Some marked as “personal”, includes some reports, letter from Thomas Hubbard to P.I. Co. Board of Directors - defending his history with the company and questioning the firing of Shepard and hiring of Morse., Dates: 7/10/13 - 6/29/20. (4/27/15) (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - “Miscellaneous - Contracts, Permits, Etc.”. List of contents on folder, includes permit affecting the 17 Mile Drive, (1916). Dates: 1900 - 1918. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - “Steamer - San Mateo”. Financial reports, miscellaneous statistics re: sine, capacity etc. of boat, survey reports, contracts and legal suit P.I. Co. v. Schubach-Hamilton Steamship Co., Dates: 1906 - Jan. 1913. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - “Real Estate - White Oaks, New Mexico”. Correspondence, quitclaim deeds, financial and survey reports, 1897 - 1919. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - “Real Estate - Buffalo, New York”. Correspondence, agreements, quitclaim deeds, judgement and decision in Erie County court case maps, deeds, abstracts of titles. (some of older material original, in excellent condition)., (1917), Dates: Jan. 15, 1875 - Oct. 2, 1922 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - “1. Old M(onterey) C(ounty) W(ater) W(orks) Statements Water Receipts and Collections and Meter Deposits Receipts 1911 and 1912, 3. Original Cost of M.W. Works 1883-1905”., 1913-1905, 2. (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - “Rights of Way - Castle Crags”. List of contents on folder, dates - 3/4/02, 6/30/16. (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - “Leases - Castle Crags”. List of contents on folder, includes correspondence, report to stockholders, inventory., Dates: 12/23/07 - 2/18/19. (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - “Miscellaneous Reports etc. - Castle Crags”. List of contents on folder, plus correspondence not listed., Dates: 1910 - 1918. (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - “Hope Ranch Data - through ”. Correspondence, maps, financial reports and original proposal of Hope Ramch as resort., 1920 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - “Hope Ranch Data- ”. Correspondence and maps., 1921 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - “Hope Ranch Data- ”. Correspondence, map, financial report., 1922-1923 (Box 19, Folder 16)
- Hope Ranch & Del Monte Properties Co.
  - “Agreements Santa Barbara - Deed of Trust”. List of contents on folder. Related correspondence and documents included., Date: 1913 - 1914. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - “Leases - Santa Barbara”. List of contents on folder. Related correspondence., 1/1/12 - 4/6/17. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - “Reports etc. - Santa Barbara”. List of contents on folder. Includes some monthly reports re: Hope Ranch Laguna Blanca Water Co., Dates: 1915 - 1919. (1919) (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - “Del Monte Properties Co., J. Beaumont - General Business”. Contain four smaller folders: A. ' - Jack Beaumont, Del Monte Properties Co., Publicity, Hotel Misc.' Correspondence and memoranda. B. `1940 - Jack Beaumont, Del Monte Properties Co., Hotel Misc. and Publicity.' Correspondence, memoranda, notes on director's meetings for minutes, real estate broker's license. C. '1939 - J. Beaumont, Del Monte Properties Co., Director's Notices'. Correspondence, memoranda and notes on director's meetings for minutes. D. `1938 - Beaumont - Director's Notices'. Correspondence, memoranda and notes for minutes., 1941 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - “Meeting Notices and Annual Shareholder's Proxies, ”. Contains six smaller folders, one for each annual meeting held in that time period. Similar contents in each: 1. sworn certificate of having mailed Annual Meeting notice, 2. copy of notice, 3. list of proxies received, 4. proxies., 1936-1941 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - “Del Monte Properties Co. - Notices of Director's Meetings and Annual Shareholder's Proxies ”. Affidavit of Publication in “The Recorder”., 1931-1937 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - “Del Monte Properties Co. - Meeting Notices and Annual Stockholder's Proxies ”. Resolutions and reports from Director's Meetings, affidavits of publication of notices of stockholder's meetings, list of stockholders., 1920-1930 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - “Del Monte Properties Co. - Meeting Notices and Annual Stockholder's Proxies, ”. Contents similar to 20-7., 1920-1925 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - “Del Monte Properties Co. - Corporation Papers 1919”. Articles of incorporation, applications before the Calif. State Corporate Dept. in order to 1. issue mortgage bonds and 2. sell its securities, schedule of release valuations, certificate of proceedings for original creation of bonded indebtedness, correspondence., Feb. 1919 - Feb. 1922. (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - “Indenture, Del Monte Properties Co. to Anglo-Calif. Trust Co., Trustee”. Securing $2,000,000, First Mortgage Sinking Fund - Six Per Cent Gold Bonds, dated April 1, 1925. (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - “Certificate of Land Sales of Del Monte Properties Co. to the Anglo-Calif. Trust Co., Trustee”. For the period of, March 1 - Sept. 1, 1925. (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - “D.M.P. Co. - Haskins and Sells Reports”. Audit of D.M.P. Co. books and accounts by Haskins and Sells, C.P.A., also reports and recommendation made re: financial situation and corporate methods, procedures by a Mr. Cyrlott of Bishop, Thane and Horse., Dates: 4/12/20 - 4/9/25. (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - “D.M.P. Co. - Fowler Report, Golf Links”. W. Herbert Fowler, British Golf Architect, made a careful examination of the Pebble Beach Gold Course and the Del Monte Old Course and makes design suggestions for improvements with maps., March 1920. (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - “Rancho Del Monte - Report and Photos”. Also known as Los Lauretes Rancho, folder contains reports, a memorandum, inventory and note on lease data concerning the ranch., Dates: 1920 - 1923. (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - “Stock Held in Trust, Morse and Fleishacker, Anglo-Calif. Trust Co.”. One affadavit certifying trusteeship signed by Fleishhacker and Morse, dated: March 15, 1920. (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - “Del Monte Lodge Construction”. Daily and accumalative statement of construction costs and code of accounts., (5/10/1918 - 8/30/1918) (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - “D.M.P. Co. - Deeds and Contracts, etc.”. List of contents on folder. Letter re: Jacks from R.G. Sproul to W.H. Crocker, Dates: 1916 - 1/1/32. 8/13/24. (Box 20, Folder 17)
- 1. Del Monte Properties Co.-2. Statements and Assessments Lists
  - “Otis Elevator - Specifications and Proposal”. For an elevator in both the Del Monte and Pacific Grove Hotels, 8/4/15. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - “Old C.B. Sloan Report”. Inspector's report re: Hotel Del Monte for C.B. Sloan, insurance brokers, May 30, 1915. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - “Sand Reports”. Formal reports and a memo re: Sand Dept. from A.J. Gunnell, 1919 - 1921. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - “Fishing Club”. Correspondence and memoranda re: Del Monte Fishing Club, 1920. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - “D.M.P. Co. Miscellaneous Reports ”. Primarily summaries or estimates of costs and expenses. Includes group photo of man at meal with a model of a golf course on the table., 1923-1927 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - “D.M.P. Co. Miscellaneous Reports 1917 - 1922”. Estimated summaries of revenue and disbursements, real estate reports on land sold and buyers, original reports on financial set-up of Del Monte Properties Co., (Jan. 1919). (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - “Report on Del Monte Forest - Coleman”. two reports (9/6 and 10/14, on treatment and possible industrial development of forest area., 1922) (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - “D.M.P. Co. Miscellaneous Data”. Interorganization reports and memoranda re: various projects and aspects of business, publicity and advertising, brochures, announcements, maps, pictures. Mostly, undated. Dates range 1919 - 1922. (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - “Stockholder's Miscellaneous”. Lost stock certificate, estate of Henry T. Scott, dates: 12/27 - 9/29. (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - “Coronado Properties”. Descriptive and financial reports re: different companies involved - all to be sold. Data covers period, 1923 - 1928. (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - “Fairmont Hotel”. Notations, architect's sketches, picture, summary of hotel's income, 1923 - 1928. (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - “S.F.B. Morse - Pt. Dume Resort Proposal ”. Correspondence, reports, rotations, proposed agreements, maps re: possible resort at Point Dume, Santa Monica Bay, Ca., 1928-1929 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - “D.M.P. Co. - Reports on Pebble Beach - Byington Ford”. Monthly, annual and special reports, letter and memorandum., Dates: 9/1/20 - 4/30/21. (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - “Reports on Hydro-electric Power Plant at San Clemente Dam on Carmel River”. Two reports: 1. on value of power 2. on amount and cost of Hydro-Electric Power. Both reports by J.A. Wilcox, accompanying correspondence and bill, dated 5/23/23 - (6/8/23). (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - “Monterey Peninsula Country Club”. The by-laws, 2/14/25. (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - “Cytherea and Hootman, Power Cruisers”. Bills of sale, charter, insurance company endorsements, pictures and blue print sketches of Cytherea., 1928 - 1929. (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - “Pebble Beach Golf Links - Real Estate”. Map of golf course and neighboring lots; and descriptions of parcels on which course is built. (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - “Report on the Power Situation at the Hotel Del Monte and the Transmission Line to Pebble Beach with a Valuation of the Transmission Line by J.A. Wilcox, ”. In black leather binder., August 1918 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - “Report on Land Owned by L., M. & V. Jacks”. In and adjacent to the City of Monterey, map included, 3/1/24. (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - “P.I. Co. Bank Statements, ”. Crocker 1st Nat'l. Bank., Jan. 1921 - June 1930 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - “Geary St., Park and Ocean Rwy. Co. Bank Statements, ”., Oct. 1916 - Dec. 1924 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - “The Oakland Water Front Co. Bank Statements, ”., Jan. 1921 - Dec. 1922 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - “Ione Coal and Iron Co. Bank Statements, ”., Oct. 1916 - Dec. 1920 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - “Ione Coal and Iron Co. Bank Statements, ”., Jan. 1921 - May 1922 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - “P.I. Co. Assessment Statements, ”. Description and acreage of all land holdings., 1918 (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - “P.I. Co. Assessment Lists, 1919”. Same contents as, 21-25. (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - “P.I. Co. Assessment Lists, 1920”. Same contents as, 21-25. (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - “P.I. Co. Assessment Lists, 1921”. Same contents as, 21-25. (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - “State Franchise Tax ”. Forms for P.I. Co. and C.H.C.Co., 1925-1940 (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - “Demand for Declaration of Property ”. For P.I. Co. only, some year's missing., 1922-1950 (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - “P.I. Co. Bank Statements, ”., Oct. 1916 - Dec. 1920 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - “Oakland Water Front Co. Bank Statements, ”., Dec. 1916 - Dec. 1920 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - “Capital Stock Tax- Return”. Copies of completed forms and notations for all P.I. Co. subsidiaries. Some correspondence with IRS., 1917 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - “Capital Stock Tax-1918 Return”. Contents similar to, 22-3. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - “Capital Stock Tax-1919 Return”. Contants similar to, 22-3. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - “Capital Stock Tax-1920 Return”. Contents similar to, 22-3. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - “Capital Stock Tax-1921 Return”. Contents similar to, 22-3. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - “Capital Stock Tax-1922 Return”. Contents similar to, 22-3. (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - “Capital Stock Tax-1923 Return”. Contents similar to, 22-3. (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - “Capital Stock Tax- Return”. Copies of forms for all P.I. Co. subsidiaries and correspondence., 1924 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - “Capital Stock Tax- Returns”. Contents similar to 22-10., 1925 and 1926 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - “Capital Stock Tax- Returns”. Contents similar to 22-10., 1933-1938 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - “Maps of Monterey Area”. First item is an index of titles of seven maps in file, descriptions of P.I. Co. land in the area., Date: circa 1916. (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - “P.I. Co. Assessment Lists ”. Description and acreage of all P.I. Co. held land., 1906 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - “California State Bank and Corporation Franchise Tax Return ”. Copies of forms and correspondence re: P.I. Co. exclusively., 1945-1956 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - “California State Contribution Return ”. Copies of form re: P.I. Co. only - many of the quarterly forms missing., 1946-1952 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - “State Franchise Tax- ”. Completed forms for all P.I. Co. subsidiaries., 1911 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - “State Franchise Tax- ”. Completed forms for all P.I. Co. subsidiaries., 1912 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - “State Franchise Tax- ”. Completed forms for all P.I. Co. subsidiaries., 1913 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - “State Franchise Tax- ”. Completed forms for all P.I. Co. subsidiaries., 1914 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - “State Franchise Tax- ”. Completed forms for all P.I. Co. subsidiaries., 1915 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - “State Franchise Tax- ”. Completed forms for all P.I. Co. subsidiaries., 1916 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - “State Franchise Tax- ”. Completed forms for all P.I. Co. subsidiaries., 1917 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - “State Franchise Tax- ”. Completed forms for all P.I. Co. subsidiaries., 1918 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - “State Franchise Tax- ”. Completed forms for all P.I. Co. subsidiaries., 1919 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - “State Franchise Tax- ”. Completed forms for all P.I. Co. subsidiaries., 1920 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - “State Franchise Tax- ”. Completed forms for all P.I. Co. subsidiaries., 1921 (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - “State Franchise Tax- ”. Completed forms for all P.I. Co. subsidiaries., 1922 (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - “State Franchise Tax- ”. Completed forms for all P.I. Co. subsidiaries., 1923 (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - “State Franchise Tax- ”. Completed forms for all P.I. Co. subsidiaries., 1924 (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - “The Monterey County Water Works to Anglo-Calif. Trust Co. Trustee, First Mortgage. Dated: ”. In booklet form., Oct. 1, 1925 (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - “Report on the Pittsburgh, Shawmut and Northern Railroad”. In black leather binder, made by Geo. H. Kimball, Consulting Engineer for Aldebert Moot, P.I. Co. attny. and representative for N.Y. holdings., 1917. (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - “Castle Crags”. In black binder, report of investigations, timber estimates, surveys and maps made by F.J. Solinsky Jr., March 1, 1917. (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - “Iron, Steel, Coal & Coke on the Pacific Coast, Vol. XVIII, Organization”. In black binder, legal procedure for incorporating steel companies and subsidiaries., March, 1918. (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - “Report of the Power, Irrigation and Domestic Water Supply Possibilities of the Carmel River”. Monterey County, Ca. by J.A.Wilcox, Jan. 18, 1918. (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - “Tax Data ”. Computations of taxes due on P.I. Co. land., 1916-1917 (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - “Dan Murphy's Property at Pebble Beach”. Maps and description of lot and deed., 1917. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - “C.H.C. Co. Weekly Financial Statements ”., Dec. 1916 - Dec. 1917 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - “C.H.C. Co. Earnings and Operations ”. Photographic copies of old financial data., 1906-1914 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - “Financial Reports P.I. Co., Seattle 1917”. Typed copy of monthly “accounts receivable” Haskins and Sells audit, Jan. - July 1917, 9/30/17. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - “Carbon Hill Coal Co. Accounts”. Monthly reports of: 1. accounts receivable, 2. checks drawn, 3. recapitulation - summarizing accounts in litigation and accounts collectable, Jan. 1917 - Dec. 1918. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - “Carbon Hill Coal Co. - Recapitulation of Mine Cost Reports”., Jan. - Sept. 1917. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - “Monthly Statements-Carbon Hill Coal Co. - Year ”., 1918 (Box 23, Folder 7)